<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on iplusfour</title>
    <link>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on iplusfour</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Jason Winget 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RadventcalendaR - Just a bit late</title>
      <link>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/radventcalendar-just-a-bit-late/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/radventcalendar-just-a-bit-late/</guid>
      <description>In early December I came across an R advent calendar for new users that was created by @KiirstiO, and decided it would be nice to do fairly short videos where I worked through the exercises in case folks got stuck.
Obviously the calendar is over now, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s still a nice, gentle introduction to R for anyone who might be new. Check out the source materials above, and my YouTube playlist can be found here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducing PowerPoint templates in Xaringan</title>
      <link>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/reproducing-powerpoint-templates-in-xaringan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/reproducing-powerpoint-templates-in-xaringan/</guid>
      <description>I recently read this tweet from @apreshill that linked to some slides by datalorax covering how to make custom themes for Xaringan, my favorite Rmarkdown presentation package. They’re really good slides and I highly recommend flipping through them.
@datalorax even has a package in development called slidex that converts the content of a PowerPoint to Rmarkdown, but what about the theme? I don’t have a magic package to solve this issue, but I thought I’d outline some steps I use to re-create PowerPoint themes in Xaringan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COWS! #TidyTuesday</title>
      <link>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/cows-tidytuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/cows-tidytuesday/</guid>
      <description>In this week’s #TidyTuesday screencast I explore some cow facts, using the emojifont package for custom symbols as plot points.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick guide to setting up OBS studio</title>
      <link>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/quick-guide-to-setting-up-obs-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/quick-guide-to-setting-up-obs-studio/</guid>
      <description>I got a little bit of interest in yesterday’s screencast for #TidyTuesday, so today I thought I’d give a simple guide to recording those screencasts with OBS studio.
The text instructions are below and here’s a short video if you’re a visual learner.
Download and install the softwareIn the lower left of the window under scenes, click + and create a new scene called screencastsUnder sources, click + and add a Display Capture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first TidyTuesday &amp; screencast!</title>
      <link>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/my-first-tidytuesday-screencast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/my-first-tidytuesday-screencast/</guid>
      <description>Like they say, long journeys start with a single step. This is my first time looking at a #TidyTuesday dataset and my first time doing an R screencast.
This week’s data is on incarceration in the US, and in just a short exploration I find some interesting features.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using rmarkdown parameters to set title, author, and date</title>
      <link>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/using-rmarkdown-parameters-to-set-title-author-and-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/using-rmarkdown-parameters-to-set-title-author-and-date/</guid>
      <description>Another quick tip today. I’m taking a look at a bunch of my Rmarkdown documents for places I can employ parameters.
For reports and other templates, you might want to parameterize the YAML header that defines the title, author, date, etc. Turns out this is more straightforward than I guessed. You just need to define the parameters near the top of the YAML, then assign them to the appropriate elements later on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write a data frame to excel without row names in R?</title>
      <link>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/how-to-write-a-data-frame-to-excel-without-row-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/how-to-write-a-data-frame-to-excel-without-row-names/</guid>
      <description>Got a question today about how to write a data frame to Excel without rownames. Seasoned R vets probably don’t even blink at this, but it’s the type of thing that I think a lot of new users struggle to overcome.
Anyhow, here are my quick and simple solutions:
The easiest is to write this to a CSV file, which will open in excel. You can use the following code to do this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barplots in the style of Tufte</title>
      <link>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/barplots-in-the-style-of-tufte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/barplots-in-the-style-of-tufte/</guid>
      <description>Lately I’ve been referencing the classic Tufte book The Visual Display of Quantitative Information. I don’t agree with everything tufte has to say, but some of his advice is fantastic.
People who consume my results like bar charts, likely because they’re familiar from Excel. I’ve been working on some ggplot2 settings that generate beautiful barplots.
Here it is:
library(ggplot2)library(viridisLite)library(dplyr)iris %&amp;gt;%group_by(Species) %&amp;gt;%summarize(mean.Sepal.Length = mean(Sepal.Length)) %&amp;gt;%ggplot(aes(x=Species, y=mean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t call it a comeback</title>
      <link>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/don-t-call-it-a-comeback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iplusfour.netlify.com/post/don-t-call-it-a-comeback/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by the excellent keynote by [@drob](https://twitter.com/drob) at rstudio::conf 2019, I’m resurrecting my long-dead blog.
Since I work mainly in R these days, I’ll be sharing useful code snippets, some #TidyTuesday exercises, and probably some other random thoughts along the way.
One thing I learned from rstudio::conf is that no R material is complete without an mtcars graph, so here you go:
library(ggplot2)ggplot(mtcars, aes(x=disp, y=mpg)) + geom_point()</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>